A Guide to the Russell Sage Foundation records, SG 3 FA413
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Grants, 1965-2016; 1; 48.23 Cubic Feet 127 letter document boxes
  - Immigration
    - Donato, Marschall, and Singer - Immigrants and Schools: Contextual Factors in Parents' School and Community Involvement (88-06-01), 2006-2010 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Ecklund - Religion and the Changing Face of American Civic Life (88-07-10), 2007-2010 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Escarse - The Health of Second Generation Mexican-Americans - Is Generational Decline Real (88-06-02), 2005-2008 (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Escobar - First-Generation Immigrant Organizations (88-08-08), 2007-2011 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Fischer - Statistical Study of Emerging New Immigrant Destinations (88-07-02), 2006-2007 (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Feliciano - The Second Generation in Middle Adulthood (88-14-03), 2013-2015 (Box 35, Folder 2)
    - Fennelly - Data Analysis and Writing of Pilot Project Data from the New Immigrant Destinations Study in Two North Carolina Counties (88-09-05), 2009-2012 (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Fix - Immigrant Children and Families on the 10th Anniversary of Welfare Reform (88-06-13), 2006-2009 (Box 36, Folder 2-3)
    - Fix - Disseminating RSF Immigration Research through the Migration Information Source (88-06-03), 2005-2009 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - Flores-Gonzalez - Destinations in an Old Gateway - The Interplay between Public and Private Actors in Shaping Local Immigration Policy (88-11-06), 2011-2012 (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Foner - Fear and Anxiety over National Identity - Contrasting North American and European Experiences and Public Debates on Immigrant and Second Generation Integration (88-12-01), 2010-2011 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Gabaccia - Conference on the Gender Ratios of International and Internal Migrants (88-08-10), 2008-2010 (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Garcia Bedolla - The Political Socialization of Immigrant Youth (88-05-18), 2005-2007 (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Gest - The Value of Citizenship - How Does Naturalization Affect Immigrants' Lives and Communities (88-13-05), 2012-2016 (Box 40, Folder 7)
      2016 grant declined
    - Goldstein - Security and Migration in the New New Jersey (88-11-05), 2011-2013 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Hero - Latino Immigrants in New Receiving Areas (88-05-05), 2004-2008 (Box 50, Folder 1-2)
    - Holton - Immigrant Assimilation Lessons from Central European Refugees Fleeing Nazism, 88-06-09, 2006-2008 (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Hopkins - A Series of Experiments to Examine the Impact of Immigrants' Language and Race on Native-Born American's Attitudes Towards the Foreign Born (88-10-03), 2009-2014 (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - RSF - Immigration and Second Generation - What Have We Learned and What's Next in Research on Children of Immigrants (88-09-06), 2009 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Ellen - Are Barrios Good or Bad - The Effects of Metropolitan Area Segregation On Hispanic Access to Opportunity, 88-15-01, 2014-2016 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Itzigsohn - Ethnic and Racial Identities among Second Generation Dominican Americans (88-02-02), 2001-2006 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - Jameson - Integration of the Undocumented and Documented in a New Destination: Utah (88-08-13), 2008-2013 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Jensen - Context, Identities, and Economic Outcomes - A Pilot Study of Dominicans in Reading, Pennsylvania (8-04-01), 2004-2008 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Junn - Mobilizing Political Identity - Ethnic Consciousness and Immigrant Political Participation (88-05-08), 2004-2008 (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - Junn - Diversity and Democracy: Context and the Puzzle of Asian American Political Engagement (88-08-14), 2007-2010 (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - Kao - Academic Readiness and School Outcomes among Second Generation Pre-School and Kindergarten Children (88-05-04), 2004-2009 (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - Kasinitz - Where Diversity Happens: Storefront Communities and Urban Change (88-10-05), 2010-2011 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Katznelson - Cities Initiative Planning Grant (83-13-01), 2012-2014 (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Kaushal - Examining the Earnings of New Mexican Immigrants in New and Traditional Destinations (88-11-04), 2011-2013 (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - Kaushal - Effect of Nurse Immigration on Employment and Earnings of U.S. Nurses (88-07-09), 2007-2010 (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Kirp - Bridging the Achievement Gap for Poor Latino Children (88-11-02), 2011-2013 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Knauer - Maya in New Bedford - Politics, Community, Identities (88-08-15), 2008-2011 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Kritz - Non-Traditional Destinations - Who is Moving Where and Why (88-07-03), 2006-2010 (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Lee, Taeku - Immigrant Incorporation and Party Identification among Latinos and Asian Americans (88-05-17), 2005-2008 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Lee, Jennifer and Zhou - Los Angeles' New Second Generation - Mobility, Identity, and the Making of a New American Metropolis (88-08-18), 2008-2013 (Box 65, Folder 2)
    - Lee, Mae - Asian Americans in Silicon Valley - The Cultural Politics of Race and Political Participation (88-08-12), 2008-2013 (Box 65, Folder 3)
    - Lee, Jennifer and Zhou - Becoming "Ethnic," Becoming "Angeleno," and/or Becoming "American" - The Multi-Faceted Experiences of Immigrant Children and the Children of Immigrants in Los Angeles (88-06-04), 2005-2009 (Box 64, Folder 2)
    - Levitt - Students from Other Lands (88-14-02), 2013-2015 (Box 65, Folder 6)
    - Liang - From Chinatown to Non-Gateway Destinations - New Patterns of Employment and Settlement for Recent Chinese Immigrants (88-10-06), 2010-2014 (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Lofstrom - What are the Effects of State Level Legislation on the Hiring of Undocumented Immigrants (88-10-07), 2011 (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - Logan - Immigrant Pathways to Political Incorporation (88-05-06), 2005-2007 (Box 68, Folder 1)
    - Logan - Generations of Immigrants and Minorites in New York (88-98-03), 1997-2004 (Box 68, Folder 2-3)
    - Logan - US 2010 - America After the First Decade of the New Century (81-09-01), 2011-2015 (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Massey - Public Use Data on Mexican Migration (88-07-08), 2005-2009 (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Massey - Transnational Identities and Behavior - An Ethnographic Comparison of First and Second Generation Latino Immigrants (88-02-07), 2004-2010 (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Massey, Fennelly, and Jones-Correa - New Immigrant Destinations - Pilot Project (88-08-07), 2008-2009 (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - McCann - Election Campaigns and the Political Incorporation of Mexican Immigrants (88-08-19), 2008-2010 (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - Mize - Toiling in the Shadows of Affluence - High-Amenity Destinations, Immiseration, and the New Gilded Age (88-14-04), 2013-2015 (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Moehling - Immigrant Incarceration 1900-1930 - Development and Analysis of Historical Data (88-10-02), 2009-2012 (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - Mollenkopf - The Immigrant Second Generation in Metropolitan New York (88-98-01), 1997-2008 (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Mollenkopf - The Immigrant Second Generation in Metropolitan New York - Papers and Products File (88-98-01), 1997-2008 (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Mollenkopf - Ford Foundation Award on this Project (88-98-01), 1998-2002 (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Mollenkopf - The Immigrant Second Generation in Metropolitan New York (88-95-04), 1996-2001 (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - Mollenkopf - Second Generation Pilot Project (88-97-01), 1997-2002 (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Mollenkopf - The Immigrant Second Generation in Comparative Perspective (88-03-02), 2002-2004 (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - Mollenkopf - Supplemental Appropriation-Bellagio II Conference Volume on Second Generation Immigrants in the EU and U.S. (88-07-06), 2009-2013 (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - Mollenkopf - Mellon Foundation Award to RSF, 1997-2002 (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - Muller - The Roles of Language and Education in Adolescent Immigrants' Civic Integration during the Transition to Adulthood (88-06-12), 2006-2011 (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - Okamoto - The Civic and Political Incorporation of Immigrants in Non-Traditional Destinations (88-08-04), 2007-2012 (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - Orgad - Cultural Defense of Nations - A Liberal Theory of Majority Rights (88-13-04), 2012-2015 (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - Ortiz - The Mexican American People - A Generation Later (88-03-04), 2003-2009 (Box 90, Folder 9)
    - Perreira - Health, Education, and the Economic Well-Being of Adolescent Immigrants (88-01-12), 2001-2007 (Box 91, Folder 5)
    - Perreira - Supplemental Appropriation - Southern Immigrant Academic Adaptation Study (88-06-07), 2006-2012 (Box 93, Folder 1-2)
    - Perreira - Southern Immigrant Academic Adaptation Longitudinal Study (88-09-07), 2009-2011 (Box 93, Folder 3)
    - Piore - A Workshop for the Working Group on Labor Standards and Migration (88-10-01), 2009-2010 (Box 94, Folder 4)
    - Portes - Transnationalism and the Political Incorporation of Latin American Immigrants in the United States (88-05-11), 2004-2007 (Box 96, Folder 1)
    - Portes - Transnational Immigrant Organizations, Political Incorporation, and Development (88-10-04), 2010-2012 (Box 95, Folder 4)
    - Portes - Transnational Organizations and the Political Incorporation of Immigrants in the United States - Phase Two (88-06-10), 2006-2007 (Box 96, Folder 2-3)
    - Portes - Immigrant Transnational Organizations and Development, (88-12-03), 2011-2013 (Box 95, Folder 5)
    - Prottas - Immigrant Political Incorporation through Grassroots Organizing (88-05-20), 2005-2007 (Box 96, Folder 6)
    - Ramakrishnan - The Civic Roots of Political Participation among Immigrants in the United States (88-05-15), 2005-2007 (Box 98, Folder 6)
    - Read - Doubly Disenfranchised - How Race/Ethnicity and Religiosity Shape Muslim American Political Incorporation (88-07-04), 2006-2010 (Box 99, Folder 3)
    - Rumbaut - Immigration and Intergenerational Mobility in Metropolitan Los Angeles (88-02-06), 2002-2007 (Box 101, Folder 4)
    - Rumbaut and Bean - Supplemental Appropriation - Immigration and Intergenerational Mobility in Metropolitan Los Angeles (88-04-04), 2003-2010 (Box 101, Folder 5, Box 102, Folder 1-2)
    - Schlidkraut - Politicized Identities and Public Opinion about Political Representation (88-12-04), 2012-2015 (Box 107, Folder 5)
    - Schlidkraut - 21st Century Americanism (88-04-03), 2003-2009 (Box 106, Folder 1)
    - Sonenshein - Immigrant Political Incorporation and Electoral Coalitions - Lessons from the 2005 Los Angeles Mayoral Race (88-05-14), 2005-2008 (Box 116, Folder 1)
    - Stevens - Conference on the Future of International Migration to OECD Countries (88-08-11), 2008-2009 (Box 116, Folder 5)
    - Street - Children of the Undocumented - Inclusion Versus Exclusion (88-13-06), 2013-2015 (Box 119, Folder 3)
    - Thomas - The Language Assimilation and Schooling Outcomes of Children Born to African Immigrant Parents (88-09-02), 2008-2011 (Box 120, Folder 2)
    - Tienda - Workshop on International Comparisons and Measurement Comparability in the Study of Child Wellbeing (88-13-01), 2012-2015 (Box 121, Folder 2)
    - Tuan - Asian Immigrants in White Families - Korean Adoptees in America (88-01-06), 2000-2007 (Box 120, Folder 6)
    - Vigdor - The Residential Segregation of Immigrant Groups in the United States, 1910-2000 (88-02-03), 2001-2011 (Box 122, Folder 5)
    - Waldinger - Pathways to Political Incorporation - Exploring the Relationship between Here and There (88-05-03), 2004-2008 (Box 124, Folder 3)
    - Waldinger - Cross-Border Connectivity and Collectivity (88-08-05), 2007-2010 (Box 124, Folder 4)
    - Winders - Latino Migration, Race and Urban Transformation in the U.S. South (88-06-06), 2005-2009 (Box 124, Folder 7)
  - Intergenerational Mobility
    - Faber - Shocks in the Geography of Opportunity: The Foreclosure Crisis and College Enrollment (83-14-09), 2014-2015 (Box 35, Folder 1)
    - Fox - Neighborhood Conditions and Upward Social Mobility (83-14-08), 2014-2015 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Gassman-Pines - The Effects of Local Job Destruction on Youth Mobility (3-14-07), 2014-2016 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Sharkey - The Effect of Violent Crime on Economic Mobility (83-14-10), 2014-2015 (Box 109, Folder 3)
  - Non-Program
    - Bailey and Danziger - Legacy of the War on Poverty (97-12-03), 2012-2013 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Brint - Christian Conservative Movement and American Democracy, 2006-2009 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Brown - Indicator of Child and Youth Well-being and the Child Trends Databank - A Midcourse Review (97-07-06), 2006-2008 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Calhoun - Task Force on the Social Issues Emerging from Hurricane Katrina (97-06-06), 2005-2007 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Camic, Gross and Lamont - Knowledge Making, Use and Evaluation in the Domains of the Social Sciences (97-07-07), 2004-2009 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Caton, Ellen, and O'Flaherty - Housing Policies that will Reduce the Volume of Homelessness and Mentally Ill in American Cities (97-08-01), 2007-2010 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Citro - Planning Meeting on the Future of Social Science Data Collection (97-09-07), 2009-2010 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Citro - Research Agenda for the Future of Social Science Data, 2010-2013 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Cole - Fifth Dimension project, 2001 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Colgrove - The Politics of Public Health: The Contemporary History of the New York City Department of Health (97-05-02), 2004-2010 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Cooper - The Handbook of Research Synthesis, Second Edition (97-06-05), 2005-2009 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Danzinger - Conference and Book to Examine the Current State of Poverty Research and Antipoverty Policies (97-08-02), 2007-2009 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Davis and Silver - Civil Liberties vs. Security: Public Opinion and the Attack on America (91-02-07), 2002-2007 (Box 24, Folder 2-3)
    - Danziger and Rouse - The Economics of the Transition to Adulthood (97-06-09), 2005-2007 (Box 29, Folder 1-2)
    - Engelhardt - Supplemental Appropriation - Creation and Maintenance of an Historical Archive at the Rockefeller Archive Center (97-03-06), 2001-2007 (Box 33, Folder 3)
    - Epstein - The Coming Fire - The 2007 Voting Rights Act Section 5 Renewal (97-05-05), 2005-2007 (Box 33, Folder 5)
    - RSF - Ethnographies of Muslim American and Arab American Communities (91-02-01), 2002-2006 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - RSF - Contribution for Hurricane Sandy Relief (97-13-05), 2013 (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Garfinkel - New York City Recovers - The New York City Social Indicators Survey, Wave Four (91-03-13), 2003-2009 (Box 38, Folder 5, Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Goroff - Conference on the Redistricting Problem (97-09-03), 2008-2010 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Grusky - The Declining Significance of Gender (85-01-25), 2001-2002 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Halle - Los Angeles and New York in the New Millennium (97-99-07), 1998-2001 (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Hartmann - Women and Retirement Security (97-06-11), 2006-2008 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Hartmann - Achieving Equity for Women - Policy Alternatives for the New Administration (97-09-05), 2009-2010 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Hauser - Revisions to the Common Rule for the Protection of Human Subjects in Research in the Behavioral and Social Sciences (97-13-02), 2012-2015 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Hedges - Social Organization of Schooling (97-01-05), 2001-2006 (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Hartmann - Making Research Count for Women - Launching the Next 25 Years (97-13-03), 2013 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Henig - Politics, Ideology, and Evidence - The New York Times-AFT Charter School Controversy (97-06-04), 2005-2008 (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Hirst - Social Aspects of Remembering (97-97-05), 1996-2005 (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Huddy - Americans Respond to Hurricane Katrina: The Subtle Political Effects of Race (97-06-02), 2005-2006 (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Jones-Correa - The Implementation of Section 203 of the Voting Rights Act (97-06-01), 2005-2007 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Korenman - Socioeconomic Effects of the Attack on the World Trade Center for New York (91-03-02), 2002-2005 (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Levi - Institutionalizing Barriers to Mobilizing Democracy (97-05-06), 2005-2008 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Lipsky - 30th Anniversary Edition of Street Level (97-09-06), 2009-2010 (Box 66, Folder 5)
    - Mack - Altered States of Consciousness (97-00-12), 2000-2005 (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Mack and Casanova - Religious-Secular Divide (97-09-01), 2008-2010 (Box 70, Folder 5)
    - Mack - Conference on International Justice, War Crimes, and Terrorism - The US Record (97-02-11), 2002-2003 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - Mack - Corruption - A Social Research Conference (97-13-01), 2013-2014 (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Mack - Fear - Its Political Uses and Abuses (91-04-01), 2003-2005 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - Mack - Fairness (97-05-04), 2004-2007 (Box 71, Folder 3)
    - Mack - Punishment - The US Record (97-07-02), 2006-2008 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    - Massey - Falling Response Rates to Social Surveys - Challenges, Implications and Solutions for Policy and Business (97-13-04), 2013 (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Milkman, Ruth - The Occupy Wall Street Movement (97-12-02), 2011-2013 (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - Mirrer - Publication of the Records of the African Free School (97-07-01), 2006-2009 (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Moore - The Legitimacy of Philanthropic Foundations - U.S. and European Perspectives (97-04-01), 2004-2006 (Box 83, Folder 1-2)
    - Moss - New Principles of Regulation - A Handbook for Policymakers (97-09-04), 2008-2009 (Box 83, Folder 5, Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Mullainathan - Behavioral Economics and Federal Government Policy (97-09-08), 2009-2012 (Box 85, Folder 2)
    - Naber - Supplemental Appropriation - Arab and Muslim Americans in San Francisco - Identity Formation and Belonging in the Aftermath of September 11 (91-02-06), 2002-2005 (Box 84, Folder 6)
    - Nacht - The Wildavsky Forum for Public Policy (97-94-03), 1993-2006 (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Neal - Robert K. Merton Archive (97-06-12), 2006-2009 (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Nelson, Richard - Complexities and Limits of Market Organization (97-02-12), 2002 (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Norman - Papers and Products (84-01-01), 2000-2002 (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - Brosnan - The Open Mind Online Digital Archive (97-07-05), 2006-2007 (Box 90, Folder 8)
    - Putnam - Diversity and Social Trust (91-02-08), 2002-2007 (Box 98, Folder 3)
    - Rasinski - Public Response to a National Tragedy (97-02-02), 2001-2004 (Box 99, Folder 1)
    - Read - Supplemental Appropriation - Multiple Identities Among Arabs in the United States (91-02-04), 2002-2007 (Box 99, Folder 4)
    - RSF - Report on Anti-Poverty Policy Tools for Government Reconstruction Efforts in the Gulf Region after Hurricane Katrina (97-06-08), 2005-2008 (Box 99, Folder 5)
    - RSF - Report on Environmental Inequality in the U.S. as Illustrated by Hurricane Katrina (97-06-07), 2005-2007 (Box 100, Folder 1)
    - Ross - Strengthening Democracy - The Key National Indicators Initiative (97-05-01), 2004-2008 (Box 101, Folder 1)
    - RSF - Centennial Volumes (97-05-08), 2005-2007 (Box 101, Folder 2)
    - RSF - Russell Sage Centennial Celebration (97-06-14), 2006-2007 (Box 101, Folder 6)
    - Sagalyn - The Politics of Planning for Rebuilding Lower Manhattan Following September 11th (91-03-05), 2002-2005 (Box 102, Folder 4)
    - Schotter - Conference on the Methodology of Experimental Economics (97-09-02), 2008-2010 (Box 106, Folder 4)
    - Skocpol - Supplemental Award - Working Group on Obama's Agenda and the Dynamics of American Politics (97-10-02), 2009-2011 (Box 109, Folder 7)
    - Skocpol - A Working Group to Examine and Analyze the Obama Administration's Efforts to Reorient U.S. Public Policy (97-10-01), 2009-2010 (Box 112, Folder 2)
    - Smeeding - Public Policy and the Future of the Family (97-03-02), 2002-2004 (Box 112, Folder 5)
    - Soares - A Twenty-First Century Strategy for Higher Education (97-07-03), 2006-2008 (Box 115, Folder 4)
    - Stapleton - Archival Storage of Russell Sage Records (97-07-08), 1995-2008 (Box 116, Folder 4)
    - Stevens - The Future of Families 2030 (97-10-03), 2009-2011 (Box 113, Folder 7, Box 117, Folder 1)
    - Stoll - Why Are There So Many Americans in Prison (97-08-04), 2007-2013 (Box 119, Folder 1)
    - Sullivan, James - Improving Evidence, Improving Outcomes Conference (97-15-01), 2015 (Box 119, Folder 4)
    - Tomaskovic-Devey - Documenting Desegregation - Equal Opportunity in Private Sector Employment Since the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (97-06-03), 2005-2013 (Box 121, Folder 4)
    - Wittek - Handbook of Rational Choice Social Research (97-06-13), 2005-2010 (Box 127, Folder 1-2)
    - RSF - Working Group on the Effects of the War on Terrorism on American Democracy (91-03-11), 2003-2009 (Box 103, Folder 6)
  - Poverty
    - Barrington - Working Poor - U.S. Historical Record (99-00-01), 2000-2001 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Beem and Mead - Welfare Reform and Political Theory (97-03-05), 2001-2005 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Bergmann and Grusky - Creating a Consistent Poverty Measure Over Time Using NAS Procedures (99-89-52), 2008 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - DiTomaso - The American Non-Dilemma - The Social Reproduction of Racial Inequality Without Racism (97-99-03), 1996-2004 (Box 25, Folder 3-4, Box 26, Folder 1-2)
    - England - Unmarried Couples with Children (83-05-04), 2004-2007 (Box 33, Folder 2)
    - Garfinkel - New York City and the Welfare State (97-02-06), 2001-2006 (Box 41, Folder 2, Box 42, Folder 1-2)
    - Hollister - Social Policy Experiments - A 25 Year Retrospective (99-94-04), 1994-2005 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Kling - Understanding the Effects of High-Poverty Neighborhoods on Youths (97-00-10), 2000-2007 (Box 60, Folder 1-2)
    - Lin - The Colors of Poverty - Why Racial and Ethnic Disparities Persist (99-06-01), 2005-2008 (Box 66, Folder 4)
    - Sullivan, Mercer - Young Fathers and the Labor Market (99-95-02), 1994-2013 (Box 118, Folder 4)
  - September 11 Initiative
    - Baker and Stockton - Detroit Arab American Study - A Companion Survey to the 2003 Detroit Area Study (91-03-06), 2002-2006 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Cainkar - A Study of the Effects of the Aftermath of the 9/11 Attacks on Arab Immigrants and Their Children in Metropolitan Chicago (91-02-05), 2002-2009 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Chin - Chinatown in Transition (91-03-03), 2002-2006 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Smith, Thomas - Conference on the Social, Psychological, and Political Impact on the American Public of the September 11th Terrorist Attacks (91-03-12), 2003-2004 (Box 115, Folder 3)
  - Social Inequality
    - Bartels - Unequal Democracy - The Politics of Economic inequality (83-05-03), 2004-2006 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Bartels, Bermeo and Pontusson - Policy Responses to the Economic Crisis in Advanced Industrial Nations (92-11-01), 2009-2012 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Berlin - New Economy and Inequality - Implications for Labor Market and Anti-Poverty Policy (83-14-02), 2013-2014 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Berkman, Acevedo-Garcia and Cutler - Social Inequality and Health (83-01-03), 2001-2005 (Box 7, Folder 3-4)
    - Bianchi, Seltzer and Holtz - Workshop on Mechanisms of Intergenerational Family Transmission of Advantage and Disadvantage (83-12-01), 2011-2012 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Biasi - School Finance Equalization and Inter-generational Mobility: Does Equal Spending Lead to Equal Opportunities? (84-14-06), 2014-2015 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Boushey - The Middle Class and Economic Growth: An Economic Paper Series (83-12-10), 2012-2013 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Bowles - Persistent Inequality in a Competitive World: Causes, Consequences, Remedies (97-00-13), 2000-2008 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Bruins - Determinants of Intergenerational Mobility, an Intra-household Perspective (83-14-11), 2014-2015 (Box 8, Folder 8)